

Profile

User-focused front-end developer, awarded with UAE Golden visa. With 3+ years of experience in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and frameworks such as React, and Next; experience in building multi-platform websites using Responsive Web Design. Knowledgeable in testing, debugging, and pipeline processes. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

Employment History

React Front-end developer, Daleel, Dubai

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

- Redesigned, enhanced, and maintained CMS, resulting in a 20% reduction in page load speeds, by utilising technologies such as code splitting and lazy loading.
- Maximised customer acceptance by 30%, by developing reports, and charts that provided real-time insights about mobile app users.
- Implemented logic to handle sign-In for external and internal users, by creating an authentication layer with AWS Auth that based on their token and role, redirected them to their corresponding dashboard.
- Assisted in scope definition, planning, estimation, and tracking.
- Developed documentation and trained new developers to maintain solutions.
- Collaborated with the product team to understand requirements and business specifications and translated them into APIs.

Next.js Front-end developer, UDroppy, Dubai

OCTOBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2022

- Designed and built reusable react components in a single-page application; that allowed to easily create new app sections and features
- Optimised the data analytics dashboard feature by including comparative date qlters which achieved a positive experience amongst 5% of users.
- Boosted search efficiency by 30% where users could filter data across the app, by integrating with Algolia search engine.
- Decreased user-reported defects by 50% after identifying and fixing root causes
- Architected product tours with React for new website sections that improved customer adoption by 40%.
- Achieved a consistent look and visual theme across the website promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.

Junior Front-end developer, Starlings, Dubai

NOVEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2021

- Developed three websites using React, while meeting monthly deadlines.
- Assessed technical feasibility for UI/UX designs.
- Troubleshot bugs and reported back to senior developers to ensure the proper functionality of the components.
- Interfaced with clients and met business requirements, by asking open-ended questions and conducting periodic reviews.
- Improved team productivity by 20% by aiding fellow interns with challenging tasks.

Details

Dubai United Arab Emirates +971581806559 julitati25@gmail.com

Links

Linkedin

<u>Portfolio</u>

Skills

React

Javascript

Next.js

Redux

Unit testing (jest, RTL)

Algolia

Material UI

Tailwind.css

Languages

Spanish

English

Assistant to Project Management, Middlesex University, Dubai

SEPTEMBER 2020 - APRIL 2020

- Provided insightful student data for teaching staff and lectures by creating an interface with JavaScript that showcased charts to document students' progress.
- Mentored students on their annual-year project by providing feedback on the topic, methodology, and annual product.
- Established the requirements for the annual year project, by researching and listing the tools students could use for gathering, designing, prototyping, testing, and development.

Education

Beng Communication and Networks, Middlesex University, Dubai

JANUARY 2018 - JUNE 2021

Awards

DAST award, Dubai Road Transport Authority (RTA), Dubai

MAY 2022

Compared two V2X (vehicle-to-everything communication) protocols and proposed a model to apply cellular communication (CV2X) in Dubai. The proposal evaluated and demonstrated through simulations how applying CV2X could prevent potential road accidents in Dubai.